wow i look rough what's up what's up what's up what's up what's up what's up why would you come
on and say no okay you got to do a request so shout out to the whole brooklyn shout out to the
whole brooklyn hello yes we're here
it's gonna be a good day it's gonna be a good day so y'all i will be in brooklyn this weekend
well friday friday is the weekend we're gonna call it friday the weekend this weekend brooklyn on
friday and i'll be hosting an event called brooklyn lives but i would rather have the individual who
is putting this together speak about it rather than myself and so when y'all are asking what's
popping this is what's popping raven take it away thank you queen it's so good to see your face
we are so excited to have you on friday translating the truth for us at brooklyn lives
you already know yeah i'm like y'all i am shaking with the power of all the ancestors right now i'm
just feeling so alive and electric about this event on friday brooklyn is an incredible city i haven't
spent much time here but we're bringing together anyone who cares about anything real in this world
right now to come together in brooklyn and to raise money for palestinians who have been displaced from
ghaza and from their homes it's just what we've been all about since 2023 for some of us decades and
years beyond this night is going to be on fire it's going to be amanda seals obviously what else do we
need first of all a b and c hello on top of that palestinian comedian sharif hassan we love him
he was at our last event courts for change totally sold out event it's going to be at littlefield
brooklyn which is such a gorgeous venue and those guys are always allies for what matters so we're
also going to be bringing on live poets to read poems from our brand new poetry anthology we put
together with 43 poets including 10 poets from ghaza who are writing from literally the rubble you guys
we've been working months to put this poetry book together you're going to get to see the first
edition of that on stage yay so excited we'll have an art auction and so many other fun things
to look forward to so do you feel like people are burnt out of their activism and if so how do we get
them reinvigorated absolutely i was going to ask you the same question i'm so glad you brought that up
because we're all feeling it y'all like we're all feeling the stress and the weight of carrying these
burdens on behalf of other folks all over the world and also just here in on turtle island like
everyday empire is visible in our daily interactions and so there's this constant burnout on top of this
really radical genocide driven burnout that we're all witnessing and feeling and so right now i really
want to center on art i want to center on what brings us joy what makes us weapons for the revolution
it's gathering in person together to touch hands to sing to dance you know what i'm saying you feel
me yeah like wait wait wait before you even go any further yeah the link where they can get tickets
link is in my bio art for palestine campaign art for palestine campaign.com you can also search
on event bright it's brooklyn lives exclamation mark so ticks at art for palestine campaign campaign
dot com that's right i have tagged this thank you you know it's so interesting that you say this because
i feel like a lot of folks have begun pushing this narrative that art has no real power or role in
activism and resistance work and i just think that that's a psyop talk about it talk about it yes i agree
completely i mean art is probably the most powerful tool we have within and against the psyop that's my
opinion i agree right you know you're a musician as well like you've you know recently just started
to put music out in a really prominent way that's very specific and literal about this message i was
just listening to psyop earlier and i'm like y'all rise catchy they're using catchy to distract us
so i'm like well let's use catchy to attract us right exactly and y'all i just want to think about
you know we just had the knicks blow up new york we just had the world cup like that's coming to a
close right now we've had so much of our collective attention dragged and drained into these spaces where
it's like team sports like people get so hype about team sports oh my god i'm like what i genuinely i feel
like i am a debbie downer with that one because i'm just like i get that it's entertaining but like
y'all are like aligning your like familial values around like a sport a team sport that you have
no stake in like at all like that's weird to me right and it's like what do we have a stake in
y'all we have a stake in our water we have a stake in our land we have a stake in the air that we breathe
we have a stake in the people who are our neighbors literally living right next to us right yes yeah and
so like you know i'm from the west coast i grew up in vancouver canada and lived in la for most of my
american life so brooklyn and new york are really new to me like what can you tell me about brooklyn
and what makes it such an important gathering point for us right now well i think on the on just a basic
note brooklyn is like the real heart of new york i feel like new york in terms of manhattan and the city
you know that is the financial aspect of new york but brooklyn is the cultural home of new york and
i think if anybody wants to argue me on that try me because brooklyn has so many different spaces
within it whether it's the indian folks in bushwick or or dominican folks in bushwick or
white girls with pink hair in bushwick um or whether you're with the caribbean folks in eastern parkway
right and then unfortunately you have the folks who are doing deed theft on eastern parkway as well
right so you also have like the latino folks in sunset park i mean there's just such a smorgasbord
of cultural and then you also have like the black american folks who are all throughout brooklyn all over
so i think when we talk about brooklyn we're really seeing like a very um literal representation of
the melting pot that people talk about that has happened here in the united states i think the
other part about brooklyn is that it's really a cultural hub like i mean when you talk about
just legendary artists there's so many that have come out of brooklyn that have taken up you know
home and they've taken space in brooklyn i mean mcs alone we're talking about biggie but then we're
also talking about most right most deaf so for me i think brooklyn has really become a very strong
arts cultural center um i think it always was but it's all it's now like taking up that identity
like no this is where you come for like real arts and real creativity and also real um resistance
movements and activism is also coming out of brooklyn right so i think it's it's it's really
become a home base for also a lot of folks who have like gone into the world and seen the madness and
been like no i need to come back to something that's more solid you know hey love it's the
brooklyn way you know i got chills i'm so excited i can't wait to experience brooklyn alive on friday
with you and to light up that space and this venue little field it's going to be amazing the events
from 6 30 to 10 so it's going to be nice tight curated you still have time for dinner before drinks
after and within that space it's like how can we activate ourselves so that we move differently when
we leave on friday night that's my only question you know no absolutely i think it's gonna be
really dope to just see how that happens right how we are watching folks take in the vibes taking the
energy and then move past that move through move with that actually i love that with that that's really
what i think a lot of folks are missing is like yes we need to be activated yes we need to be
organized yes we need to be focused however we have burnout that's just a real that's like a real
physical thing that's not just like an individual thing and so there has to be restorative uh places
restorative justice restorative energy restorative artistry and that's what brooklyn lives is about
it sounds like to me absolutely i mean would you agree that being in the presence of deep aligned
community is restorative just right that's why i have my patreon that's why you know even when i was
doing my show smart funny and black it was that and i started a new show called radical rhythms
existence i'm sorry radical rhythms experience every second tuesday every second one i can't talk
every second wednesday in harlem and we had the first one last week and it was just so dope to see how
generous people were with their energy with their time also with their with their thoughts you know
we were i was doing stand up we're doing energy work we're talking about freedom and folks just locked
in and yeah so many people told me after you know like i didn't realize that i really needed this
i really didn't realize you know how how much this would like bring me back into you know just kind of like
um stabilizing our our nervous system right like that part that that part might be the whole part
you know and like you're an artist and our nervous systems are so sensitive to the pain of the world
do you know what i mean like how do you use art to move through your own experiences of burnout or fatigue
or you know tell me about that well from for me i mean the thing about an artist is that if you're not
creating you're just kind of not in alignment and so if you're not in alignment you are much more
susceptible to being disrupted right to being distracted to being disturbed etc so it's not even
like i'm like oh let me do art to deal with burnout it's more so let me do the thing that
keeps me fortified and that keeps me stored like solid and sturdy because i know these people want
to co-op my energy i know that they're trying to disrupt my nervous system you know i know that
they're trying to make they're trying to control me in ways where they think i can't control myself
and so when i'm doing art and i am continuously creative it allows me to
like be on alignment on my path and that makes it much harder so that when the weird
shit happens you're like ah yeah yes no no thank you yeah not even thank you sometimes just straight
up no no and that's in general right that's not even just with like the politics that's with partners
that's with bosses you know like working and career etc like that's why it's just so important to find
where creativity lives in you i do believe that even if you don't consider yourself a career artist
finding where creativity lives in you is an imperative aspect to you being in alignment
all of us have creative capabilities i always say this raven like they were drawing on walls girl
right it was dust and blood like like they were it was that meant it was it was a necessity yes we've got
to do it so for us to be living in this time and folks are not doing even if your creativity is
you know making macaroni art like find something and creativity cannot can also be gardening right
creativity has like the but it's just the creativity for for those who don't understand
creativity is making something from nothing okay i'm about to get deep are you ready go let's go let's go
know so we are here on this earth we don't know why the we are here many of us somebody does but
they ain't told us so they're holding it down however in our ability to live as humans we have
a we have senses that we need to lean into and when people talk about god they are constantly talking
about making something from nothing we no matter what god you believe in it ends up being we are in a
vision of god right all the books all the people they all come back to that right if we're in a vision
of god and we are leaning into our power that we are being bestowed upon in order to carry that will
out then we have to be leaning into all of those powers if if the god image is one that makes something
from nothing then you too have to be leaning into your ability to make something from nothing whether that's
growing plants whether that's drawing right whether that's sewing whether that is doing metal works i
don't know it's just the thought process of having an idea and leaning into it with your love to make
it happen and to bring it into existence because all we can do is grow that's all we are here in my
opinion to actually do is to continue to create growth and anything against that we got to get rid of and so
we have to have these restorative spaces to bring us into that god work so we can continue to fight
the folks that are trying to take it out of us amen to that come on aho ashay thank you so much
oh my gosh you said one of my favorite p words girl which is power and this is what i want to
communicate to add to what you've shared is that they want us placid and pacified and prone and we
need to be upright and loud and uplifted and turning that fire on you know like and that thing and i
feel like for a lot of folks they they want to do that but they haven't figured out like how you know
and so what's been really cool is to see folks who are now curious to figure out how and so like
that's the type of stuff that we're doing at brooklyn lives on friday that's right 6 30. like
we are freaking live sorry we are giving energy to do that you know i mean for those who are really
trying to figure out how do i how do i restore my energy how to reclaim my power um that's what we're
going to be doing yeah so come come get a big dose really it's going to be like uh not a small doses
a big dose y'all i think the tickets the tickets uh website is down here in the pinned comment and
if you know people in brooklyn if you know folks in the tri-state area put them on spread the word
let them know i'm going to be hosting brooklyn lives tell them some more because you know people
are coming in so tell people absolutely they can get all your favorite most juiciest types of people
in one room poetry music dancing art auction palestinian artists y'all we have created a
poetry book and a virtual art gallery and postcards featuring incredible art look at this one from
palestinian artists and artists in the diaspora it is going to be just like a nourishing juicy juicy
night at littlefield brooklyn this is a gorgeous venue it is we're gonna have a live portrait artist
as well who's gonna be painting live portraits it's gonna be just like micro festival vibes but with
macro focus on what really matters you know what i'm you know what i'm saying yes we don't have time
we don't have time to putz around and sing kumbaya like without taking action right now you know we really
don't like the kumbaya days you know so i've been talking to people about how like every time you
come on this internet and you release like so it's like a release valve that's fucking with us like so
people really be like oh i'm going to comment on this thing that pissed me off and i know that in
your mind you think you're just commenting but i really have come to believe that what's actually
happening is you're releasing the the pressure valve that's that you actually need to build up
in order to fight right so it's like a false sense of action yeah you feel like you're being productive
when you're just adding your voice to the mix but especially on these little phones like what is
how is that really bringing my heart closer to your heart that's why i stopped doing my show views from
amanda lands because i realized i was just not that i wasn't like a valuable part of the noise but it
still felt like i can do something that has a bit more of a lasting effect which was to me which is to
me music and that can actually get people on a more visceral level because i know that there's a lot of
people that are telling geopolitical news and facts and you know i wouldn't necessarily say like i'm the
best um i know there's a lot of folks that that's their passion and at this point y'all i just feel
like we have to be finding our passion and existing in it and that's like an imperative part of this
because the authenticity we live in a lie so on my basic basic basic level raven i'm just like
the best way to find a lie is with the truth right so if we live in a lie like they're lying all the
time they were lying about the state of hormones they're lying about they're lying about cspire they're
lying about all of this stuff so on a very very basic level and that's why my album is called truth
translator we have to be existing in truth like at all times and that also comes in kind of just
figuring out a way to to give your passion a space in your life i know that it's not always easy and
practical because these folks these motherfuckers have made it their business to keep us really locked
into labor and producing for them etc so it becomes an act of defiance just to even figure out like
how do i make time how do i make room for the thing that is closest and most authentic to me
to exist and that's why for people who are close to brooklyn who are in the heart of this city who
have the feeling of i can change something here even if it is just in my neighborhood even if it is
just the way i show up to my office like come out and meet us and like receive amanda's wisdom and
beauty and power on stage you're gonna be singing a couple songs from your new album do you want to
tell us a little bit more about what we can expect from you on stage on three days i mean i'll be
hosting so you'll always get jokes i mean you're always gonna get jokes and you're always gonna get
gems gems and jokes jokes and gems and uh you know now that i have the album and there's gonna be a
mic and a dj i'm gonna have to perform so oh that's just gonna be what it is so i've been performing two
songs and um you know i'm excited to actually perform perform because i really haven't i've
just been doing like listening sessions where i've just been like kind of peeping like poking
in singing so this will be the first time that i'm like singing the song hey i'm gonna make sure
i know all those lyrics beforehand so that you at least have one major hype girl in the front yo
that's gonna be so fun no i'm i'm so happy also just to be back in new york i know you said
this is like your first living your first foray in new york i am coming back so i've been back in
new york since the 20s in 2024 and you know when i was in new york that's what made new york so dope
was that the artistry was so loud you know the artistry was so consistent everybody was doing
something you was always building something up from you know the ground up and folks were always there
to be like all right so we're doing now i'm riding with you yes in la everything is how does this make
money real real how does this get me proximity to the illusion of fame and like if they can't figure
that out they don't do it right and they might screw you over too that part like i remember i had
a web series and my agent was like okay we're gonna get funding for the web series and i was like okay and
so we went about trying to get funding for the web series and then we didn't get funding for
the web series and so i was like okay i'm gonna crowdfund and she was like i don't think that's a
good idea i don't think it's a good look i was like why isn't there a good look for who and she was
like well i just think it makes you look like you're desperate and i was like but i am
like i am desperate to get his work out there so i'm gonna i'm gonna take the opportunities or
or create the opportunities i should say if they don't come to me and she was so she felt some type
of way but like in new york it was like i want to do a web series and folks said all right how are we
gonna do it you know that's the difference yes and that's what makes our team at art for palestine
so special this is like a homegrown group this is my homies daniela ryan james eric adela i can name
them all off the top of my head because these are homies who have just built this organization
grassroots our executive director is a virgo she's the most organized colombian little chiquita you will
ever meet we love her shout out to daniela who is putting this all together and i came into the org
after it was already a year off the ground and with my vision and connection and you know i'm an artist
as well myself and art for palestine was designed by artists for artists you know and so we're
showcasing artists from palestine but also from all over the world in different campaigns we just did
a poetry anthology i'm looking forward to maybe doing compilation albums different events in different
communities you feel me like we could write children's books we could do out any kind of media
that we want to really carry this message our team is so equipped to put art in the world and we all
love and live for it and that's why i'm here i'll produce a song for one of the poetry album if you
do it let's do that i love that idea do you ever do spoken words yourself are you in the poetry space
you're saying you do not know my history i do but like i want you to tell us about it yeah i was on
deaf poetry jam and yeah i did two seasons of deaf poetry and i began as a spoken word poet in my
adult life i have poetry book um but i don't like performing spoken word um i actually like i'm
really good at it but it's just not my it's like i don't know it's just not my favorite medium but i
spent a lot of time in the spoken word you know space and when i was um coming up in college like
that was really the space i was in so shout out to like folks like mahogany brown who i've known from
back then and who is now like just one of my sisters and really well really welcomed me back
in new york in a way that like people who i thought were my friends did not really yeah like people i
thought were my friends were like oh like you want help moving in like i thought you hired somebody to
do that i don't have time for that i'm like what like is that really how we treat people whereas you
have mahogany who's like when can i come through how about when do you want to come and do what
would the ancestors say your one woman show at lincoln center like what are we what are we doing
and so that is something i've missed about new york is and that i had in the and that i did have when
i was in the poetry community just this real fervor for like creating space for us to do our thing
so i love that you are and also at the end of the day you know poetry is such an incredibly
necessary part of the arts and a part of the palestinian artistic voice specifically right so
i love that you um are creating space for that amazing thank you for sharing more about that and
just helping make the connection of like no matter what medium that you're in there's always truth
to be translated in some way you feel me yeah i mean there's just um there's just going to be a
really great amalgam of artistry all in the same moving in the same direction this weekend and this
this friday sorry and i think that's the other thing too is like the intentionality right like
we're all there with our highest vibration with our highest skills and talents all moving toward the
same direction which is liberation for palestine which is liberation for all right so collective
liberation and when we do that like for folks who are watching like that that's the same as praying
right right that's the same as like gandalf with the staff saying you shall not pass like it's just
it's power concentrated and i really genuinely know and not just believe but i know that we are powerful
beings and so when we are connecting our power we're just we're stronger we're more effective
absolutely thank you so much thank you for coming to brooklyn lives this friday amanda and like
just being you i think your authenticity is really the medicine that models for us what it looks like to
bust through these walls and just live your truth
in the words of a very famous brooklynite kick in the door waving the four four okay y'all kick in
the door waving the four four all you heard was papa don't hit me no more hey so brooklyn all my
peoples please go to art for palestinecampaign.com it's pinned at the bottom get your tickets and come join
us i know a lot of y'all are even just new to the palestine movement so this is also a great way for
you to just become immersed to make new friends to find ways to be a part of the network of resistance
i know a lot of folks are always like i want to help but i don't know how here's a way to do that
and if you are not in brooklyn and you want to help but you don't know how i take it anyway how about
that because these funds support the work and a lot of us may not have the wherewithal to do the work of
organizing and finding out how to make sure that this support is getting to this place and so what
we do is we lift up we platform and we support folks who do do that work and that is how we keep
the flow going so really a part to be really proud to be a part of this thank you for having me and i
i will see you on friday i cannot wait queen it's gonna be lynn thank you send love to the whole art
for palestine campaign family and i can't wait to see y'all on friday and we are going to lift up free
free free palestine free free palestine yallah habibi i will see you on friday inshallah see you inshallah
take care y'all thanks amanda bye everyone